根据真实事件改编
只有死者才能看到战争终结 ――柏拉图
1992年 东非 索马里
多年来的部落战争 造成史无前例的饥荒
三十万人死于饥荒
势力最强大的军阀艾迪德 掌控了首都摩加迪沙
他抢走国际组织运送的粮食 以饥荒作为他的武器
他的恶行引起公愤
两万名美国海军陆战队员被派到索马里 协助运送粮食并维持治安
1993年4月
艾迪德等到美国海军陆战队一撤退
便立刻向其余的联合国维和部队开战
在6月 艾迪德的民兵伏击和屠杀了24名巴基斯坦士兵
并开始攻击美国人
8月底 美军派遣精锐部队
三角洲部队 第75游骑兵团 以及第160特种作战航空团
前往摩加迪沙推翻艾迪德 并重建秩序
该任务原定为三个星期便结束
但六个星期后 华盛顿失去耐性
黑  鹰  坠  落
1993年10月2日 星期六
红十字会粮食分发中心
那里
There.
九点钟方向有武装车
Technicals, nine o'clock.
该死 你看到吗
Oh, shit! Did you see that?
机长 在九点钟方向有平民遭到攻击
Chief, we got unarmed civilians getting shot down here at nine o'clock.
看到了 但我们不能干涉
I got it, Matt. I don't think we can touch this.
这些粮食是属于穆罕默德・法拉赫・艾迪德的 快滚回家吧
指挥官 这里是超级64号
Command, Super 64...
民兵在粮食分发中心扫射平民
we got militia shooting unarmed civilians down at the food distribution center.
请求准许攻击
Request permission to engage.
超级64号 你有受到攻击吗
Super 64, are you taking fire? Over.
没有 指挥官
Negative, command.
那里属于联合国管辖 我们不能干涉
U.N. 's jurisdiction, 64. We cannot intervene.
- 返回基地 - 收到
- Return to base. Over. - Roger.
64号返回基地
64 returning.
摩加迪沙 巴卡拉市集 艾迪德势力范围
可以走了 奥图先生
他要走了
Leaving.
先生
继续开
我恐怕要迟到
待会儿再打给你
加里森将军
General Garrison?
谢了 我有了
No, no, thanks. I got one.
这是古巴雪茄
But these are Cuban.
上好的保利瓦雪茄
Bolivar Belicoso.
这也是
So is this.
那是迈阿密产的 我的朋友 这没古巴的好
Miami, my friend, is not Cuba.
你们老是抓不到艾迪德
I see not catching Aidid is becoming a routine.
这次我们要抓的不是艾迪德 我们要抓的是你
We weren't trying to catch Aidid. We were trying to catch you.
我
Me?
我有这么重要吗
But am I that important?
我想破头也想不出我有多重要
I hardly think so.
- 你是个生意人 - 只是混口饭吃而已
- You're just a businessman. - Trying to make a living.
对 而且你贩卖枪枝给艾迪德的民兵
Yeah. Selling guns to Aidid's militia.
你来了多久
You've been here, what?
六个星期
Six weeks?
六星期来你一直想抓到他
Six weeks you are trying to catch the general.
到处张帖悬赏海报
You put up reward posters.
两万五千美元 这算什么 你想演《终结追杀令》吗
$25,000. What is this? Gunfight at the K.O. Corral?
是《绝命追杀令》
It's the O.K. Corral.
你以为把我抓来他就会自首
Do you think bringing me in will make him suddenly come to you?
乖乖束手就擒
Make him more agreeable?
你知道他在哪里
You know where he sleeps.
你资助他的一切 包括民兵
You pay for his beds, much less his militia.
我们逮不到他就不会离开索马里
We're not leaving Somalia till we find him.
我们一定会逮到他
And we will find him.
别以为我不是喝自来水长大的…
Don't make the mistake of thinking because I grew up without running water...
就认为我是个笨蛋
I am simple, General.
我对历史很了解
I do know something about history.
你看到吗 我们在创造明天
See all this? It's simply shaping tomorrow.
指克林顿总统
一个没有阿肯色州白小子干涉我们内政的明天
A tomorrow without a lot of Arkansas white boys' ideas in it.
这点我倒不清楚 我是德州人
Well, I wouldn't know about that. I'm from Texas.
加里森将军 你们不该来这儿
Mr. Garrison, I think you shouldn't have come here.
这是内战
This is civil war.
这是我们的战争
This is our war.
不是你们的
Not yours.
三十万人死亡
300,000 dead and counting.
这不是战争 奥图先生 这是种族屠杀
That's not a war, Mr. Atto. That's genocide.
喝茶吧
Now, you enjoy that tea, you hear?
你觉得他怎样
How'd he strike you?
彬彬有礼 冷酷无情
Urbane, sophisticated, cruel.
他是一条大鱼
Yeah, he's a good catch.
时间一久 艾迪德就会感到受制了
It'll take time, but Aidid will feel the loss.
我们没有太多时间
I'm not sure time is something we got in great supply.
这里比伊拉克的情形要复杂
This isn't lraq, you know. Much more complicated than that.
但华盛顿官员可不这么想
Boss, most of Washington might disagree.
这个星期他们每天早上都打电话来
I'm just saying they've been calling for these dang situation reports...
要那该死的形势报告
every morning this week.
你就告诉他们说战争一触即发
Well, tell them the situation is fragile.
摩加迪沙机场 美国陆军指挥总部
女士们 先生们 先大家好 我是克里夫・"猫王"・渥尔考特
Ladies and gentlemen, my name is Cliff "Elvis" Wolcott.
本次航班的机长
I'll be your pilot this afternoon.
这架黑鹰直升机是非吸烟区
Federal regulations has designated the non-smoking Black Hawk helicopter.
凡经常飞摩加迪沙的本公司会员
For those of you moved on Mogadishu frequent flyer program...
可以累积100点的哩程优惠
you'll be earning 100 free credits this afternoon.
呕吐袋就放在前座的椅背
And as always, the air sickness bags are located in the seatback in front of you.
1号发动机正常 克里夫 检查2号发动机
Number one indications are good, Cliff. Put her on two.
没问题
You're still clear.
61号 这里是64号 使用超高频无线电
61, this is 64. Go to UHF secure.
我有个坏消息
I've got some bad news.
Limo为豪华轿车
"Limo"是一个词 杜兰特 别再跟我罗唆
"Limo" is a word, Durant. I don't want to hear about it.
那是缩写 不是一个词
It is not a word. It's an abbreviation of a word.
"Limo"是常用语
"Limo" is a word in common usage.
拼字游戏的规则是接受常用语 我的好朋友
That is the key phrase in Scrabble, my good friend. Common usage.
不 字典查不到就不算
No, if it's not in the dictionary it doesn't count!
字典查不到也算
It doesn't have to be in the dictionary!
字典查不到就不算
It does have to be in the dictionary!
听着 等我回基地我就把这个词给剔除掉
Listen, when we get back to the base, it's coming off the board.
此处Limo指男性器官
你敢碰我的"Limo" 我就揍你 懂吗
You touch my "limo" and I'll spank you, Nightstalker. You hear me?
你有种揍我才怪呢
Yeah, promises.
好美的海滩
That's a nice beach down there.
海水怎样
How's the water?
很暖和 到处都是鲨鱼
Yeah, it's nice and warm. And it's loaded with sharks.
这敢情好
That's great.
- 你觉得这很好玩吗 - 不
- Thinks he's funny. - Yeah. Well, I don't.
听到吗
Hear that?
- 紧张吗 - 我严阵以待
- Nervous? - I'm ready to go, man.
多么适合作战的一天
Beautiful day to fight.
- 名字 - 托迪
- Name. - Todd.
- 姓 - 布莱克博德
- Last name. - Blackburn.
名字是托迪
First name, Todd.
- 这里怎样 - 什么怎样
- So, what's it like? - What's what like?
摩加迪沙 有仗打吗
Mogadishu. The fighting.
- 士兵证号码 - 72163427
- Serial number. - 72163427.
把Mogadishu砍掉一半读成Mog后 就和停尸房Morgue的读音相近了
首先 大家都会说"莫格" 而不会说"摩加迪沙"
Firstly, it's "the Mog" or simply "Mog." No one calls it Mogadishu here.
其次 就是有仗打也没我的份 所以别问我
Secondly, I wouldn't know about the fighting, so don't ask.
为什么
Why not?
我叫你别问了
Didn't I just say, "Don't ask"?
你不是游骑兵
You're not a Ranger.
我当了6年的游骑兵
I am a Ranger. Six years.
我在巴拿马追捕过诺列加 还参加过海湾战争
I was in Panama chasing down Noriega, and in the Gulf.
我可是个老兵 伙计
I'm a vet, my friend.
参加过战斗
In combat?
你真像个12岁小孩子 我来解释一下：
Look, kid, you look like you're about 12, so let me explain something to you.
我有一种特殊的才能 不必参与战斗
I have a rare and mysterious skill that precludes me from going into missions.
打字
Typing.
- 你会打字吗 - 不会
- Can you type? - No.
- 生日 - 1975年2月27日
- Date of birth. - 2-27-75.
我是来踢爆坏人的卵蛋的
Well, I'm here to kick some ass.
回去吧
Let's bring it in.
干得漂亮 伙计
Nice, man! Very smooth!
一枪就打穿发动机了
Single shot through the engine block.
真可惜 那辆吉普车挺帅的
Shit, that's a shame. That was a nice jeep.
停止射击 停止射击
Cease fire! Cease fire!
检查武器
草泥马的"三角洲"
Fucking Delta.
埃利斯曼中士
Sergeant Eversmann.
- 中士 - 什么事
- Sergeant. - Yeah?
我是一等兵布莱克博德
Private First Class Blackburn.
什么事
Yeah?
我来报到
Reporting for duty.
你应该向比尔斯中尉报到
Not to me you're not. You're reporting to Lt. Beales.
他应该就在附近
He should be around here somewhere.
我把他交给你了
Can I leave him with you?
好吧
Yeah, go ahead.
- 你带武器了吗 - 带了 长官
- You brought your weapon. - Yes, sir.
我不累 我能练靶吗
Want me to shoot? I'm rested.
- 什么时候到的 - 刚到
- When did you get in? - Just now, Sarg'nt.
先做重要的事
First things first.
这会是你在非洲最好的朋友
This will be your best friend in all of Africa.
它叫"牛蛙"
It's called BullFrog.
抹一点到脸上
Get some on over here, all right?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
嘿 施密德 帮我带一下队
Hey, Schmid! Take over for me, would you?
好了 先去把东西放好
All right. Let's get you unpacked.
谁饿了
Hey, who's hungry?
这算什么 纳税人出钱组织的三角洲野餐队吗
What is this, Sarg'nt? Another taxpayer-funded Delta safari?
Jeff Sanderson为电影中化名 这位三级军士长真名叫Paul Howe 退役后开了自己的战术培训学校
- 如果加里森将军问起可别说 - 我问起呢
- Not if General Garrison is asking. - I'm asking.
用餐愉快 上尉
Have a nice meal, Captain.
- 嘿 伙计 大家都在排队 - 我知道
- Hey, man, there's a line. - I know.
- 你这是插队 - 我也知道
- Well, this isn't the back of it. - Yeah, I know.
军士 军士
Sergeant. Sergeant.
这是怎么回事
What's going on here?
我们练靶的时候打到了一只野猪
Some aerial target practice, sir. Didn't want to leave it behind.
我是说你的武器
I'm talking about your weapon.
hot weapon指武器上了膛同时又打开了保险
三角洲也不能拿一把开着保险的枪到处乱晃
Now, Delta or no Delta, that's a hot weapon.
你应该很清楚 在基地里 任何时候枪都要关着保险
You know better than that. Safety should be on at all times on base.
这一段是编导在瞎掰 现实中D-BOYS都是非常注意保险的
比如Sanderson的原型Paul Howe在他的经验里都十分强调保险的作用
这就是我的"保险"
Well, this is my safety, sir.
别管他 他好几天没吃饭了
Let it go, sir. The guy hasn't eaten in a couple of days.
你那帮三角小崽子只是一群目无纪律的牛仔
You Delta boys are a bunch of undisciplined cowboys.
我告诉你
Let me tell you something, Sarg'nt.
到了前线 你会需要游骑兵的支援的
When we get on the five-yard line, you're going to need my Rangers.
你们最好学学什么是团队精神
So y'all better learn to be team players.
我说完了
We're done here.
说呀 你说这是保险
Speak up. You say this is your safety?
这是我的靴子
Well, this is my boot, son.
小心我用这只靴子把你踢爆
And it will fit up your asses with the proper amount of force.
- 这是新泽西口音吗 - 拜托 我很努力耶
- Is that a Jersey accent? - I'm trying to do this, give me a break.
把太阳眼镜脱掉
Take those sunglasses off, soldier.
"三角洲"喜欢戴Ｏ记眼镜 那是他们的事
Delta wants to wear Oakleys, that's their business.
别让我再看到你戴
I don't want to see them on you again. Hoo-ah?
这把枪上了膛
Is that a hot weapon?
你下了吗
Is that your move?
手还没离棋啊
Is my hand on the piece?
再下三步我就赢了
I can mate you in three whatever you do.
你自己小心点吧 我正盯着你的"女王"呢
I'd keep my eye on that queen before counseling with the others.
她躺在那儿等着呢
Well, she's just lying in wait.
进退维谷吧 戈登
Stranded and condemned, Gordy.
该你了
Your move.
克里布斯
Cribbs.
伊格斯
Yikes.
你画得越来越好了
It's good. You're really improving.
不过我有一个建议
If I may make a suggestion... Observation.
说吧
Go ahead.
- 这是童话故事 对吧 - 没错
- It's a children's book, right? - Right.
这会把小孩子吓得屁滚尿流
They are not supposed to scare the living shit out of the children.
这里说到我们的的骑士…
This is the part of the story where our knight, our warrior...
正要屠掉独眼巨龙
is about to slay the one-eyed dragon.
本来就很可怕 而且我女儿最喜欢了
That's scary. Besides, my daughter loves this stuff.
我以为你上礼拜就画完了
Thought you finished that last week.
你说完了吗
You done?
就快冲到十码线了
Hey, we are at the 10-yard line here, men.
明白吗
You understand?
讥讽美式足球运动员的智商
你会数数吗 一 二 十
Can you count? One, two, ten.
美式足球里持球跑动进攻的球员
我的跑卫呢
Okay? Where are my running backs?
我的跑卫哪去了
Where are my running backs?
我没看到你做礼拜
Hey, I didn't see you at church on Sunday, soldier.
你有别的事吗
You had something more important to do?
礼拜天一定要做礼拜
Not on Sunday, you don't. Not anymore.
别给我落跑 了解吗
I will make you believe, you understand?
很好笑
Pretty funny, hoo-ah?
你学得很像 很像我
It was a good impression. I recognize myself.
你们继续吧
All right, carry on.
- 我要跟你讲话 - 是 长官
- I'd like a word, specialist. - Sir.
你知道谁有指挥权吧
Tell me, Pilla, you understand why we have a chain of command, don't you?
知道 长官
Roger that, sir.
你敢再取笑我…
'Cause if I ever see you undermine me again...
我就要你把马桶舔干净
you'll be cleaning latrines with your tongue...
保证你一个月吃不下饭
till you can't taste the difference between shit and French fries.
- 明白吗 - 明白了
- Are we clear? - Hoo-ah, sir.
好了
All right.
听好
Listen to this:
当一个索马里人杀了人 他的部落就欠对方部落一百只骆驼
If one skinny kills another skinny, his clan owes the dead guy's clan a hundred camels.
一百只骆驼
A hundred camels.
我连一只都不给
Camels. I wouldn't pay one camel.
这儿的人一定都欠了一屁股的骆驼债
Must be a lot of fucking camel debt.
这是真的吗
Is that really true, Lieutenant?
去问埃利斯曼中士 他喜欢非洲人
Ask Sgt. Eversmann. He likes the skinnies.
埃利斯曼中士 那是真的吗?
Sgt. Eversmann, you really like the skinnies?
不是喜欢不喜欢的问题 我尊重他们
It's not that I like them or I don't like them. I respect them.
你们意识到埃利斯曼中士是个理想主义者了吧
See, what you guys fail to realize is the sergeant is a bit of an idealist.
他相信这项任务的使命对吧 中士
He believes in this mission down to his very bones. Don't you, Sergeant?
这些人没有工作
Look, these people, they have no jobs...
没有食物 教育和未来
no food, no education, no future.
我只是觉得我们有两个选择
I just figure that, I mean, we have two things that we can do.
帮助他们
We can either help...
或是眼睁睁看着他们自相残杀
or we can sit back and watch the country destroy itself on CNN.
对吧
Right?
我不知道 我是来打仗的
I don't know about you guys, but I was trained to fight.
你不是吗
Are you trained to fight, Sergeant?
我是来改善世界的
Well, I think I was trained to make a difference, Kurth.
他真的很有理想
Like the man said, he's an idealist.
等等 我最爱这一段
Oh, wait. This is my favorite part.
滚远一点
Stay away from the cans!
去死吧 猪头
Die, gas-pumper!
给我滚远一点
Stay away from those cans!
比尔斯
Beales!
不 退后
No, no, stay back, stay back.
他的癫痫症发作了 拿东西让他咬着
He's having a seizure. Put something in his mouth.
约翰 没事了…没事了
John, it's okay. John, it's okay. It's okay.
10月3日 星期天 清晨5:45
他没事了 不过他得退伍
Well, he'll be fine. But not in this army.
他有癫痫症 我得送他回家
He's out of the game. He's epileptic, going home.
按照马克・鲍顿原著里的解释 Chalk为游骑兵的一个12人战斗小分队
但根据美国陆军作战条令 Chalk为"黑鹰"在空中突击中运载的一个11人小分队
我要你来带领他的小分队
I'm putting you in charge of his chalk.
- 有什么问题吗 - 没有 长官
- You got a problem with that? - No, sir.
这个责任很重大
Now, it's a big responsibility.
你的弟兄们依赖你
Your men are gonna look to you to make the right decisions.
他们的命都在你手上
Their lives depend on it.
好了
All right.
"Rangers, lead the way" 乃游骑兵口号
- 游骑兵 做先锋 - 勇往直前
- Rangers lead the way, sir. - All the way.
祝好运
Good luck, Sergeant.
巴卡拉市集 哈瓦迪街 艾迪德民兵的据点
艾迪德势力的高级成员今天下午三点可能要开会
A long anticipated meeting of Aidid's senior cabinet may take place today at 1500 hours.
我说"可能"是因为…
I say "may" because we all know by now...
根据目前的情报 一切都不确定
with the intel we get on the street, nothing is certain.
这是三方确定的情报
This is actual intel confirmed by three sources.
两名高层成员可能会在场
Two tier-one personalities may be present:
艾迪德的政治顾问奥玛・萨拉德
Omar Salad, Aidid's top political advisor...
内政部长阿迪・哈桑・阿瓦利
and Abdi Hassan Awale, lnterior Minister.
他们是我们的目标
These are the guys we're after.
今天就行动
Today we go.
任务计划和以前一样
Same mission template as before.
15:45时 三角洲的突击小组攻入敌方建筑物
1545, Assault Force Delta will infiltrate the target building...
逮捕里面所有的嫌疑人
and seize all suspects within.
警戒部队为游骑兵的四个小分队 由斯蒂尔上尉指挥
Security Force Rangers: 4 Ranger chalks, under the command of Captain Steele...
在15:46时滑降到地面
will rope in at 1546...
在目标建筑外围的四个角建立防线
and hold a four-corner perimeter around the target building.
任何人不得进出
No one gets in or out.
撤退部队
Extraction Force:
麦肯奈特中校的悍马车队在15:47时开进哈瓦迪街
Lt. Colonel McKnight's humvee column will drive into the city at 1547...
停在奥林匹克旅馆前
on Hawlwadig Road and hold just short of the Olympic Hotel here.
等待指示
Wait for the green light.
当三角洲部队突击成功
Now once Delta gives the word...
麦肯奈特的手下前往目标建筑
McKnight's column will move to the target building...
把犯人架上车
and load the prisoners on flatbed trucks.
把犯人架上车后
Immediately after the prisoners are loaded...
游骑兵的四个小分队立即到目标大楼集合
the four Ranger chalks will collapse back to the target building...
一起上悍马车队
load up on humvees...
然后地面部队就一路返回基地
and the entire ground force will exfil the 3 miles back to base.
行动时间预计不足30分钟
Mission time from incursion to extraction, no longer than 30 minutes.
我原本请求调动装甲车辆和AC-130"幽灵"炮艇机支援
Now, I had requested light armor and AC-130 Spectre gunships...
但华盛顿却不同意
but Washington, in all its wisdom, decided against this.
他们认为太高调了
Too high-profile.
所以行动将由"黑鹰"和"小鸟"
So Black Hawks and Little Birds will provide the air cover...
用Minigun和2.75英寸火箭提供空中支援
with miniguns and 2.75 rockets.
哈勒尔上校
Colonel Harrell.
C-2即"指挥"Commando和"控制"Control
在C-2直升机上 马修斯上校负责空中支援的调度
In the C-2 bird, Colonel Matthews will coordinate the air mission...
而我负责指挥地面部队
and I will coordinate ground forces.
马修斯上校
Colonel Matthews.
本次任务的代号为"艾琳"
Mission launch code word is lrene.
有问题吗
Questions?
目标是哪栋建筑
Which building is it, sir?
目前还不清楚准确的目标建筑
Exactly which building, we're confirming right now.
只知道是巴卡拉市集附近
Somewhere around the Bakara Market.
我不能替他们决定开会的时间地点
I don't choose the time or place of their meetings.
我不是这个意思
I didn't say a word, sir.
大家听好 你们到了巴卡拉市集
Make no mistake, once you're in the Bakara Market...
就等于进入战区
you're in an entirely hostile district.
千万别低估敌人实力
Don't underestimate their capabilities.
进入市集之前都不是战区
Now we'll be going through friendly neighborhoods before we hit the market...
千万切记交战规则 遭到攻击后才能还击
so remember the rules of engagement: No one fires unless fired upon.
完成这件任务吧
Now, let's go get this thing done.
祝大家好运
Good luck, gentlemen.
还有什么不满吗 丹尼
What's the matter, Danny? Something you don't like?
没有"幽灵"炮艇机 而且是白天的行动…
No Spectre gunships, daylight instead of night...
那些索马里佬在下午特别精神
late afternoon when they're all fucked up on khat...
而那里又是艾迪德的根据地 火力集中
only part of the city Aidid can mount a serious counter-attack on short notice...
- 我还能什么不满的 - 人生不如意事十常八九
- What's not to like? - Life's imperfect.
你们在半空中只是不如意
Yeah. For you two, circling above it at 500 feet, it's imperfect.
我们在地面就苦不堪言
Down in the street, it's unforgiving.
那时候除了打个招呼你们还能帮我什么
You two say hello to me from up there.
你死不了
You'll do fine.
谢谢
Thanks.
要搞什么
What the fuck, Smith?
什么
Well? Well, what?
我们要出动了吗
We going?
- 我干嘛告诉你 - 因为我想知道
- Why should I tell you that? - Because I'm me.
好吧 下午三点 市中心
Yeah. 3:00. Downtown.
- 巴卡拉市集 - 好吧
- Bakara Market. - All right.
听着 史密斯 我要你全力支持我
Listen, Smith, I need you to back me up out there today, all right?
提高警觉
Keep sharp.
遵命 埃利斯曼中士
Yes, sir, Sergeant Eversmann.
这次行动是小意思啦
Ev, it's going to be nothing, man.
小意思
Nothing.
嘿
Hey.
坐下
Sit down.
这是怎么回事
How'd this happen?
我不太愿意想起来
I don't even remember.
觉得自己就像个傻瓜 玩乒乓球的时候
Think I was just goofing off. Playing ping-pong, I think.
撞到混凝土台角上了
Sort of hit the concrete.
好吧
Okay.
你可以把它治好吗 我们今天要出动
You can fix it up though. We're going out today.
你哪也去不了
You're not going anywhere.
可恶
Jesus Christ!
磨咖啡豆的关键是不能磨得太细或太粗
It's all in the grind, Sizemore. Can't be too fine, can't be too coarse.
这是一种技巧
This, my friend, is a science.
我可是相信征兵广告的
I mean, you're looking at the guy that believed the commercials.
美国征兵广告的口号：Be all you can be
你看 "去做你力所能及的事"嘛
You know, about "be all you can be."
结果我在整个"海湾风暴"期间都在煮咖啡
I made coffee through Desert Storm.
在巴拿马也是煮咖啡 而别的游骑兵都在打仗
I made coffee through Panama, while everyone else got to fight got to be a Ranger.
我却只能煮黑咖啡 替别人拿奶精
Now it's "Grimesy, black, one sugar" or "Grimesy, got a powdered anywhere?"
- 怎么回事 - 打乒乓球受伤了
- What happened to you? - Ping-Pong accident.
什么
What?
你猜怎么着
So guess what.
你的愿望实现了 你今天要出动了
Your wish has been granted. You're going out today.
少唬我了
You're fucking me.
你要接替我的位置 操纵M60机枪
You're taking my place assisting the 60 gunner.
埃利斯曼中士叫你快去收拾好装备
Sergeant Eversmann said to get your stuff and get ready.
你想要打仗 不是吗
It's what you wanted, isn't it?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
Hell, yeah.
格里姆斯 紧跟着瓦戴尔 你是他的弹药手
Grimesy, I want you to stick with Waddell and give him ammo when he needs it.
别担心 索马里人的枪法都很烂
I wouldn't worry about that. Generally speaking, Somalis can't shoot for shit.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
小心别被他们的石头扔到就行
Just watch out for the sammys throwing the rocks, and you'll be fine.
会很好玩的
Might even be fun.
让"三角洲"打头阵 我们只是支援他们
D-boys do their thing now. All we got to do is cover them.
直升机也会掩护我们的
Choppers going to cover us, and we'll be all right.
我知道我是第一次当分队长
Look, you guys, I know this is my first time as chalk leader...
但我们不是第一次出任务
but, this isn't our first time out together. This is serious.
我们是游骑兵 不是什么狗屁预备役军官
We're Rangers, not some sorry-ass JROTC.
我们是精锐的
We're elite.
大家要好好表现
Let's act like it out there.
有其他问题吗
Any questions?
我们会完满完成的
We're going to be okay.
去收拾装备 行动吧
All right, grab your gear. Let's move out.
不必带水壶 很快就会回来了
You're not going to need that, dude. We're not out there long enough.
也用不着带那个
You're not gonna need that, either.
天黑前就会回来
We'll be back before dark.
你还不如多带些大麻和啤酒
You might as well take dope and beer instead.
什么
What?
弹药啦 我是说多带些弹药啦
Ammo, dude. Take ammo.
我告诉你吧 格里姆斯 你身上已经背着五十磅的装备了
Let me tell you something, Grimes. You got about 50 pounds of gear as it is.
没必要再增加额外的十二磅
You don't need another 12.
我不知道你有什么打算 反正我是不会被人在背后打枪的
I don't know about you, but I don't plan on getting shot in the back running away.
好吧 我也会注意的
Well, I better keep mine in.
格里姆斯
Hey, Grimes.
最重要的是
The most important thing:
朝着大家射击的方向开枪
Just remember, when everybody else is shooting, shoot in the same direction.
好
All right.
你瞧 他在靴子帖上血型
Look at this. He's taping his blood type to his boots.
- 这要触霉头的 - 不 他很聪明
- That's bad luck. - No, it's smart.
"三角洲"都这么做
All Delta do that.
写遗书也是触霉头的
That's bad luck, too, man.
快走吧
Come on, let's go.
幸好你不是左撇子 阿多尼斯
It's a good thing you're right-handed, Adonis.
- 不然你就打不了飞机啦 - 你真会说笑
- If not, I don't know what you'd do. - You're a funny guy, man.
- 我不替你拿遗书 - 咱们可是说好的
- I'm not taking no death letter. - We have a deal.
回来后再还给你
I'll give it to you back in an hour.
- 布莱克博德 感觉怎样 - 很兴奋
- Blackburn, you okay? - Excited.
这是好事 我命中注定就是当兵打仗的料
In a good way. I've been training my whole life for this.
你开枪打过人吗
You ever shot at anybody before?
没有
No, sir.
我也没
Me neither.
下午2:29
他靠得住吗
Think he's reliable?
瞧着吧 这是他第一次出任务
Well, we'll see. It's his first time out.
联合作战指挥中心
- 叫他把收音机关掉 - 是 长官
- Tell him to turn his damn radio off. - Yes, sir.
叫他把收音机关掉
Tell him to turn his radio off.
阿迪 关掉收音机
Abdi, you need to turn your radio off.
这里是史黛芬和兰迪 请留言 谢谢
Hi. You've reached Stephanie and Randy, leave us a message. Thank you.
老婆 是我 你在吗
Hey, baby, it's me. Are you there?
你在的话就快接
Pick up if you're there.
我只是打来看你过得怎样
I'm just calling to check up on you, make sure everything's all right.
两小时后再打给你
I'll call you in a couple hours.
你最好别睡着了
You'd better not be sleeping.
该你了 兰迪
Your move, Randy.
我好想你
I'm missing you.
我爱你
I love you, baby.
喂 喂
Hello? Hello?
谢谢 博德
Thanks, bud.
- 对不起 我没看到你在后面 - 没关系
- Sorry, I didn't see you there. - It's all right.
这有点好笑
You know, it's kind of funny.
这里蓝天白云 椰林树影 水清沙幼
Beautiful beach, beautiful sun.
几乎是个度假的好地方
Could almost be a good place to visit.
几乎是
Almost.
你认为我们不该来
You don't think we should be here.
你知道我怎么想吗 我怎么想并不重要
You know what I think? It don't really matter what I think.
当第一颗子弹从你头顶上呼啸而过时…
Once that first bullet goes past your head, politics and all that shit...
就什么屁事都不重要了
just goes right out the window.
我只想着完成任务
I just want to do it right today.
打起精神来 让弟兄们活着回来
Just watch your corner. Get all your men back here alive.
就是这儿了 还是汽车抛锚了
Now, is this supposed to be the place, or did his car just take a dump?
阿迪 请回答
Abdi, come in.
你听到吗 这里就是目标吗
Abdi, can you hear me? Is this the place?
阿迪
Abdi, come in.
听到吗
Can you hear me? Abdi.
请回答 是这里吗
Abdi, come in. Is this the place?
我右手边 咖啡厅楼上
To my right hand side, above the cafe.
他说就是这里
Sir, he says this is the building.
他确定
He's certain?
阿迪 你要确定才行
Abdi, you need to be sure.
你确定
Are you sure?
目标在我左边两条街口外
Well, it's down the road, two blocks over on my left.
不过民兵太多了
But there's too many militia.
我一靠近他们就会开枪
If I go closer, they might shoot me.
他说目标在两个街口外
Now he's saying the building's actually a couple blocks down...
但他担心太靠近的话会被人开枪
but if he's seen outside it, he'll be shot.
他不敢靠近的话我会亲手向他开枪
I'll fucking shoot him myself a couple blocks down.
叫他把车子停在目标建筑门口
Tell him I want his skinny ass parked in front of the damn building.
他不去就拿不到钱
He's not getting paid till he does exactly that.
离目标区域三英里 不要走小路
It's three miles to the target area. We're never off the main roads.
到了K4交通圆环后先向北然后往东
At the K-four traffic circle, we turn north, then east on National...
在那儿等候劫出犯人
and we wait until extraction of prisoners is complete here.
然后全队开进
Then we roll up in force on Hawlwadig...
载上犯人和地面部队
we load the prisoners, and then the assault-blocking forces...
把他们一起带回来
and bring them back.
一小时内就可以返回基地
Home in an hour. Okay?
指19世纪时期子弹横飞的美国西部
敌人肯定会反击 到时巴卡拉市集就会像狂野西部一样
Now there will be some shooting. Bakara Market is the Wild West.
但你们开枪要小心 那儿有平民
But be careful what you shoot at because people do live there.
上一个线民在酒吧里玩俄罗斯轮盘 结果把自己脑袋给嘣掉了
Last one of these guys shot himself in the head playing Russian roulette in a bar.
长官 他停车了
Sir, the vehicle is stopped.
这次是真正的目标吗 他确定吗
So this is the real deal now. He's sure this time?
- 他的声音听起来已经是吓得屁滚尿流了 - 好了 看来这次是对的了
- He sounds scared shitless. - Good. That's always a good sign.
对头 他发出暗号了
That's it. That's our signal.
行动吧
All right.
QRF是快速反应部队的缩写
让快反部队升空
All QRF out of the airspace.
命令所有快反部队升空
全体注意 "艾琳" 重复 "艾琳"
All units, lrene. I say again, lrene.
检查完毕 巴伯51号准备好升空 星41号准备好升空
Check in when ready. Barber 51 up and ready. Star 41 up and ready.
"艾琳"
Irene!
收到 "艾琳"
Copy, lrene.
他妈的艾琳
Fucking lrene!
来吧
Come on.
祝你们好运 小伙子们
Good luck, boys.
小心点
Be careful.
决不抛弃同袍
No one gets left behind.
怎么回事
What's wrong?
以前他从不跟我们道别的
Nothing. He's just never done that before.
该死的
Aw, fuck!
走吧
Let's go.
史崔克中士 出发吧
Sergeant Struecker. Let's roll.
格里姆斯
Grimesy!
两分钟
Two minutes.
他们干嘛烧轮胎
Why are they burning tires?
通知民兵我们要来了
Signals to the militia that we're coming!
56号 看来到了地上会有许多人欢迎我们的
Okay, 56, looks like there's some friendlies on the ground.
我能拦截到他们的对话
Looks like I've got a tally on the voice intercept.
一分钟
One minute.
约翰・格里森姆――《终极证人》
你在干嘛
What's that for?
上次滑降时我差点把舌头给咬断
Last rope, I almost bit my tongue off.
准备降落
Touching base.
两英尺 一英尺
Two feet, one foot...
安全
clear.
下午3:42
"小鸟"安全着陆
Little birds touching down at target.
滑降
Ropes!
上 上 上
Go! Go! Go!
第一小队正在着地 第二小队正准备着地
Chalk One troops are on the deck. Chalk Two deployed.
这是麦肯奈特 U64已经到达目标区域
This is McKnight. Uniform 64 approaching staging area.
趴下 趴下
Down! Get down!
Down! Stay down!
趴下 所有人都趴下
Get down! Everybody down!
你 趴下
You, down!
趴下
Get down!
到一楼了
On the floor.
斯蒂尔上尉 叫你的手下别向我们开火
Captain Steele, tell your men to stop firing at us.
26号 这里是64号 停火 你们正在向"三角洲"开火
26, this is 64. Cease fire. You're firing at Delta.
重复 停火 完毕
I repeat, cease fire. Over.
你靠近点 格里姆斯
You stay close to that ammo, Grimesy.
是算是正常的交火吗
Is this normal enemy fire?
不 我起码见过十趟比这更糟的
No, no, this is 10 times worse than I've ever seen it.
快走 走
Let's go, let's go!
格里姆斯 别害怕
Grimesy! No fear!
你当我是菜鸟么
Oh, yeah, right!
游骑兵已经在四个街角建立起防线
Rangers securing perimeter. Four corners.
中校 他们在朝我们开火
Colonel, they're shooting at us!
那就打回去啊
Well, shoot back!
这里是64号 游骑兵分队已经落地 正在建立防线
This is 64. Chalks on the ground, going into holding pattern.
收到
Roger that.
这里是62号 游骑兵分队已经送到 现在准备好空中掩护
This is 62, delivered chalks. Going to cover pattern.
超级62号 到部队上空提供狙击手掩护
Super 62, take up an overhead pattern to provide sniper cover. Over.
这里是超级65号 游骑兵分队已经落地 正在建立防线
This is Super 65. Chalks on the ground, going into holding pattern.
下去 布莱克博德 下去 下去
Go, Blackburn, go! Go!
下去 布莱克博德
Go, Blackburn!
RPG
RPG!
抓紧啦
Hold on!
不
No!
C-2 有人掉下去了
C-2, we got a man fallen.
- 超级61号 你还留在那儿是想挨打吗 - 布莱克博德
- Super-61, you're a sitting duck there. - Blackburn!
请在空中提供狙击手掩护
Take up overhead pattern to provide sniper cover. Over.
收到 我们出来了
Roger that. 61 coming out.
13号 前进 我要你们马上赶到街口北边
13, go ahead. I need you to move to the north of the street.
快去北面 那儿 就在那儿
Right to the north. Right there. Right there. Over.
军医 施密德军医
Doc! Doc Schmid!
快过来
Come on!
施密德 有人受伤了
Schmid, we got a man hit.
- 哪里中弹了 - 不是 他是摔下来了
- Where's he hit? - He's not. He fell.
- 什么 - 他摔下来了
- What? - He fell.
你怎么不开枪
Why aren't you shooting?
他们还没有向我们开枪
We're not being shot at yet!
你怎么分辨
How can you tell?
子弹"咻"一声就表示打得很近
A hiss means it's close.
如果是"啪啦"一声就表示…
A snap means...
现在他们向我们开枪了
Now they're shooting at us!
杰利顿
Galentine!
帮我接斯蒂尔上尉
Get me Captain Steele! Get me Captain Steele!
J64号 这里是J25号 请回答
Juliet 64, this is Juliet 25. Come in. Over.
布莱克博德 听到吗
Blackburn, can you hear me?
J64号 这里是25号 请回答
Juliet 64, this is 25. Come in. Over.
我联络不到他
I can't get him!
J64 这里是第四小队 有一个人受伤了
Juliet 64, this is Chalk Four! We've got a man down!
我们要把他带离这里
We need to get him out of here! Over.
这里是64号 请再说一遍
This is 64. Say again, 25. Over.
有一个人受伤了
We've got a man down! Over.
别紧张 25号 冷静点
Take a breath, 25, and calm down. Over.
- 有人受伤了 - 听不清 25号
- Man down! - Missed that, 25.
- 操 - 再说一遍
- Fuck it. - Say again.
马特 我们离悍马还有很远
Matt, it's a long way to the humvees!
这儿有担架 把他抬去目标建筑那里
We'll get a stretcher in here. Get him to the target building.
好吧
Okay.
他说什么
What did he say?
超级61号 有一人在地面受了伤
Super 61, we got a man wounded on the ground.
- 担架 - 快拿担架
- Stretcher! - Get me a stretcher!
快点 担架
Come on. Stretcher.
快 快
Come on, come on!
抓住另一边
Grab this end!
走吧
Let's go!
- 好 - 走
- All right. - Go.
把他抬去悍马那里 我们守住这个街角
Get him to the humvees. We'll hold down the corner.
快把他抬上车
Up to the humvees! Now!
快 快
Go! Go!
继续跑 格里姆斯 跑
Keep moving, Grimes! Run!
- 安全 - 走
- Secure! - Let's move out!
快起来 快走
Everybody up! Let's go!
走吧
Come on!
快走
Let's go! Let's move!
- 格里姆斯 跑 - 来了
- Grimes, run! - All right.
C-2 这里是超级61号 开始在目标区域上空盘旋
C-2, this is Super 61, beginning my orbit of the target area.
收到
Roger that.
第四小队 请清除你们的负责区域
Chalk Four, clear for a clear. Coming in.
K11号 这里是61号 掩护我们带犯人出来
Kilo 11, this is 61, providing cover for prisoner extract. Over.
green light是"开始行动"的通用语
K64号 "绿灯"
Kilo 64, green light.
- 准备出来了 - 收到 K11号 准备好了
- Ready for extraction. Over. - Roger that, Kilo 11. Will relay.
很好 逮到他们了
That's it. We got them.
U64号 准备撤出
Uniform 64, ready for extraction. Over.
收到 他们叫我们了 快去吧
Roger that. There's the call. Let's move out!
- 出发吧 - 坐好
- Let's move out! - Hold on.
- 还要多久 - 五分钟
- How much longer? - Five minutes, sir.
- 什么 - 五分钟
- What? - Five minutes.
绝对不止五分钟
Nothing takes five minutes!
他是怎么了
What happened to him?
- 他没抓到绳索 摔下去了 - 怎么搞的
- He fell! Missed the rope! - How'd he do that?
把他抬上悍马 帮帮忙
Put him in that humvee! Grimes, give him a hand!
走吧 快走
Let's go! Let's move it!
快 动作快点
Move, move! Come on! Move!
把他抬上去
Get him in there!
行啦 快走
Get ready to move!
走 快走
Go! Everybody move! Move!
快上车
Get the fuck up!
格里姆斯 来过来
Grimes! Come on!
格里姆斯 格里姆斯
Grimes! Grimes!
我靠
Fuck this!
靠
Fuck!
快走
Let's go.
快点
Come on!
快走
Go! Move it!
快点
Move!
R64号 我要三辆悍马车先把伤员送回去
Romeo 64, I need to send out three humvees with a critical casualty.
他的伤势很重 必须立刻护送
He looks real bad. I need to evac now.
收到 U64
Roger that, Uniform 64.
我会派一组直升机去掩护你
We'll chop a team of gun ships to you. Over.
收到
Roger that.
山德森 我需要一些人去护卫悍马车队
Hey, Sanderson, I need extra security on these humvees!
我去 我带我的小队下去增援他们
I'll go. I'll take my team, make sure they get back okay.
去吧
Do it.
史崔克 你给车队带路
Struecker, you're lead humvee.
快上车 我们要回基地
First three vehicles mount up, we're moving back to base.
走吧
Move out!
进展怎样 没问题吧 史崔克
How are things going? Things okay there, Struecker?
我现在没时间谈 上校
I don't want to talk about it now, Colonel!
我忙着呢
I'm busy.
皮尔中士中弹了
Sergeant Pilla's hit!
老天 他伤得好重
Christ, he's fucked up!
谁中弹了
Is anyone hit?
史崔克 快回答
Struecker, talk to me!
是皮尔中士
It's Sergeant Pilla!
他的状况如何
What's his status?
他死了
He's dead.
皮尔死了 长官
Pilla's dead, sir.
C-2 这里是麦肯奈特 多明尼克・皮尔阵亡
C-2, this is McKnight. We have a KIA Dominick Pilla. Over.
收到
Roger that.
快接手五零机枪
Get on that 50!
快去接手五零机枪
Someone get on that 50!
我来
It's mine.
三个家伙拿着RPG在接近你
Three guys with RPGs, coming up on your side now!
稳住
Stay with it!
这里是61号 我被击中了
This is 61. I'm hit. I'm hit.
超级61号被击中 渥尔考特的直升机被击中
Super 61 is hit. He is hit. Wolcott's bird is hit.
快把输油阀关掉
You want to pull those PCLs off-line or what?
撑下去啊
Right, babe.
Come on.
61号在坠落
61 going down.
61号在坠落 她在坠落
61 is going down. She is going down.
- 超级61号正在坠落 - 61号在坠落
- Super 61 is going down. - 61 is going down.
超级61号正在坠落
Super 61 is going down.
61号正在坠落 重复 超级61号正在坠落
61 is going down. I repeat, Super 61 going down.
61号正在坠落
61 is going down.
抓紧
Hold on!
有一架黑鹰坠毁了
We got a Black Hawk down. We got a Black Hawk down.
超级61号直升机在市区坠毁
Super 61 is down. We got a bird down in the city.
超级61号坠落在地面
Super 61 is on the deck now.
派MH-6到现场搜救生还者
Get an MH-six on site. Check for survivors.
派出搜救直升机
Send in the SAR bird.
派出地面部队到坠机地点建立防线
I want ground forces to move and secure a new perimeter around that crash site.
你们能引导车队吗?
Can you guide the convoy in there?
收到
Roger that.
快去呀
Well, move quick.
民兵会蜂拥而上围攻他们
The whole damn city will be coming down on top of them.
星41号 请试着降落在坠机地点
Star 41, come inbound and see if you can land at the crash site.
收到 星41号马上去
Roger that. Star 41 inbound.
我们已经失了先机
We just lost the initiative.
25号 这里是64号
25, this is 64. Over.
这里是25号
This is 25. Over.
25号 第四小队最靠近坠机地点
25, Chalk Four is closest to the crash site. Over.
64号 我看不到坠机地点
64, I can't see the crash site. Over.
25号 就在你的正东方 你能找到的
25, it's due east of you. You will find it.
留下一些人继续防守
Leave a security element in place.
带其他人赶往坠机地点
Take the rest of your chalk on foot to the crash.
搜救生还者 守卫那一区 其它小队会过去会合的
Check for survivors. Secure the area. All other chalks will follow. Over.
25号 你听到吗
25, do you read me? Over.
收到
Roger that.
杰利顿 施密德
Galentine! Schmid!
去找尤瑞克
Go get Yurek.
去找汤布里
Get Twombly.
有一架黑鹰坠毁了
Hey, there's a Black Hawk down.
汤布里和尼尔森留守
Twombly, Nelson, you're gonna stay here.
你们守在这个街角 然后跟悍马车队一起撤离
You're gonna hold this corner and then exfil with the humvees.
杰利顿 施密德 你们跟我一起走 都明白了吗 出发
Galentine, Schmid, you're coming with me. All right? Let's go.
为什么要我留守
How come I got to stay back here?
因为你很可靠
Because you're dependable.
好吧
All right...
出发
let's go!
我恨我自己可靠
I hate being dependable, man.
J25号 你的西面有敌人与你们并行前进
Juliet 25, hostiles advancing, parallel west to your position.
有妇女儿童混在其中
Be advised, women and children among them. Over.
靠着墙走
Hit the wall.
敌袭
Incoming!
手榴弹
Grenade!
走
Go.
还有人在里面
We still got guys inside!
赶快 我还要赶去坠机地点
All right, all right, I'm gonna go to the crash.
你带其他人去 我继续装载犯人
You take the rest of the team. I'll finish loading the prisoners.
不 我们要一起去坠机地点
Negative! We're gonna proceed to the crash site together.
守住防线 然后等悍马车队来 对吗 长官
Secure the perimeter, wait for the humvees. Right, sir?
- 收到 - 跟我上
- Roger that. - Follow my lead.
军士 听到吗
Sarg'nt, are you receiving me?
听到了 我们马上走
Yeah, I heard you. We should be leaving soon.
好了 我们要赶快行动
All right, we need to move out now!
等犯人装完了我就去坠机地点接你们
I'll finish loading the prisoners and pick you up at the crash site!
出发吧
Let's move out!
出发了 快走
Moving out! Go!
快上车 快上车
Get in! Get in!
快点
Move!
八点钟方向
Eight o'clock!
格里姆斯 别靠着墙
Hey, Grimes, stay away from the walls.
喂 格里姆斯 你没事吧
Hey, Grimes. You okay?
没事
Yeah!
走吧 马多克斯
Let's go, Maddox.
- C-2 车队出发了 - 收到
- C-2, convoy's moving out. - Roger that.
马多克斯 看看这些猪头 这些白痴
Maddox, look at these jerks! These idiots!
快 转右 马多克斯 转右
Go, go! Right, Maddox, right!
汤布里 车队走了
Twombly, the convoy is leaving!
嘿 汤布里
Hey, Twombly!
什么
What?
- 我想他们肯定忘了我们 - 什么
- I think they've forgotten us. - What?
算了 当我没说
It doesn't matter.
63号 敌人从四面八方赶过去
63, confirm. We've got Skinnies moving in from all directions.
我们要赶快支援他们
We need to get them help now.
索马里人正赶往渥尔考特的坠机地点
Indigenous personnel advancing to Wolcott crash site.
请重复
Say again. Over.
一大堆人正蜂拥而上
A lot of people closing in.
第四小队离那儿还有多远
How far is Chalk Four from the crash site?
- 六个街口 - 他们要加快
- Six blocks, sir. - They need to haul ass.
趴下 趴下
Get down! Get down!
斯科特 你没事吧
Scotty, are you okay?
别回去
No, don't go back!
趴下 趴下
Get down! Get down!
武装车
Technicals!
看到了
Got them!
六点钟方向 快走
Six o'clock! Move, move!
快离开这儿
Come on. Get out of the way.
快走
Go, go, go!
Go, go!
快点
Come on!
尤瑞克 快离开
Yurek, leaving!
快点
Come on!
U64号 左转 左转
Uniform 64, left turn. Left turn.
R64号 你得告诉我该在哪条该死的街上才往左转
Romeo 64, I need to know before I get to the goddamn street!
你得先停一下 消息发出时延迟
You have to slow down. There's a delay.
侦察机的情报是先送到联合指挥中心 然后再转到我这儿
From the time directions are relayed from surveillance to JOC, then to me.
我们不能停下来 我们正受到猛烈的攻击
We can't slow down! We're taking heavy enemy fire!
我们不能停下来
We can't slow down!
丹尼 我正在接收"奥利安"侦察机的情报
Danny, I'm getting information from Orion surveillance above.
此次行动中有1架P3 Orion反潜预警机负责战场监控
快告诉我该怎么到坠机地点
So get me my fucking directions to the crash site!
丹尼 等一下 我这里看不清你的位置
Danny, hold on. I no longer have the best view of your route.
那快赶去看得到的地方呀 该死的
Just get your ass in the right place, God damn it!
现在史崔克的车队怎样了
What in the hell is the status of Struecker's humvees?
勒尔上校 史崔克的车队还有多久会回到基地
Colonel Harrell, ETA to base, Struecker's column.
就快到了
ETA to base momentarily.
开门
Open the gate!
- 把他抬下车 - 快
- Get him out! Let's go! Let's go! - Come on.
小心他的头
Watch his head.
小心
Easy.
- 布莱克博德 你听到吗 - 快带他去治疗
- Blackburn. Blackburn, you hear me? - Get him to a medic.
星41号正在坠机地点抢救伤者
Star 41 is at the crash site to evacuate the injured. Over.
收到
Roger that.
我来帮你
I got you.
小心
Easy.
杰利顿 你还行吧
Galentine, you all right?
杰利顿 寇兹 跟我上 掩护火力
Galentine, Kurth, with me! Cover fire, now.
全力掩护
Full cover!
有几个人在里面
How many are in there?
两名驾驶员死了 两名机工长受伤
Two pilots are dead, the two crew chiefs are wounded!
他伤得很重 我们先把他救出来
This guy's hurt bad. We gotta get out of here now.
好 去吧
All right. Go ahead.
26号 26号 这里是25号 那辆武装车是你打的吗
26, 26, this is 25. Is that you shooting up the technicals? Over.
26号收到
This is 26. Roger that.
迪托马索 占领东南角 我们要建立起防线
DiTomasso, take the southeast corner. We're setting up a perimeter. Over.
26号收到 马上过去
This is 26. Roger that. Moving there now.
出发
Move out!
斯蒂尔上尉 斯蒂尔上尉 请回答
Captain Steele. Captain Steele, come in.
这里是64号 请说吧 25号
Go ahead, 25. This is 64.
伤者两名 两名直升机驾驶员阵亡
We got two wounded and we got both the pilots dead in the chopper!
这里需要医疗救援
We need a medivac over here now!
25号告诉我那里在激烈交火 直升机没法降落 你要先守住防线
25 is telling me it's too hot to land a bird. You gotta secure the perimeter first. Over.
悍马车队呢
Where are the humvees?
25号 车队一定会到
Be advised, 25, the convoy will be there.
他们正遭到猛烈攻击 64号呼叫完毕
They're encountering a lot of resistance. 64 out.
- 快接手五零机枪 - 你很快就会看到前面的坠机地点了
- Get the 50 up! - You should see the crash directly ahead.
我前面只看到路障
All I see is a roadblock!
好吧 我另找一条路
All right, I'll have to figure out another way.
快建立防线 把伤员载上车
Give me a defensive perimeter so we can load the wounded.
奥西克 快开枪
Fire your weapon, Othic!
跟我女儿说叫她们安心
Tell my girls I'll be okay.
奥西克
Othic!
军医
Medic!
军医 军医
Medic! Medic!
乔伊斯 快过来帮我把他抬起来
Joyce! Joyce! Come on, help me pick him up!
快把我们带出这条该死的街道 坠机地点到底在哪里
Get us off this fucking street! Where's the crash site? Say again.
直走两百米
Keep going straight 200 meters.
收到
Roger that.
走吧
Let's go!
快走吧 该死的 走
Let's go, God damn it, let's go!
嘿 汤布里 过来
Hey, Twombles. Come here.
悍马不会回来了
The humvees ain't coming back, dude.
什么
What?
我们要去找他们吗
Were we supposed to go to them?
我以为他们会来找我们呢
I thought they were supposed to come to us.
可恶
Shit.
- 我们想我们该去找他们了 - 可恶
- I think we're supposed to go to them. - Shit.
好吧 我们去坠机地点
Okay, let's go to the crash site.
好的
Okay.
别在我耳边开枪 我都快聋了
Just don't fire that thing so close to my head. I can barely hear as it is.
好 出发
Okay, move out.
可恶 趴下
Shit! Get down!
我才警告过你 别靠这么近打 如果你再这样…
What did I just tell you? I swear to God if you do that again...
闭嘴
Shut up!
尼尔森 你没事吧
You okay? Nelson.
你没事吧
You all right?
你说什么
What?
搜救直升机正在现场展开救援
Search and rescue bird on station inserting medics.
快上
Go!
上 上
Go, go!
该死的 C-2 这里是68号 我们被击中了
Son of a bitch. C-2, this is 68. We've been hit.
超级68号 你的旋翼冒烟了
Super 68, there is smoke coming from the top of your rotor.
- 建议你立刻返航 - 收到
- Advise you to come out now. - Roger.
最后一个下去了
Dropping last man.
阿特 我看到十二点钟方向有扛着RPG的人 你看得到吗
Art, I've got skinnies with RPGs at 12 o'clock. Can you see them?
看到了 左转九十度
Got them. Give me 90 degrees left.
68号现在退出战场
68 coming out.
超级68号现在退出
Super 68 is out. Over.
韦基 情况如何
Hey, Wilkie, what's the situation in there?
驾驶员都死了
Both pilots are dead.
25号 我们无法移动他们 马丁
25, we can't move these guys, Matty.
如果我们勉强搬动他们会让他们没命的
We'll kill them just carrying them.
- 就在这儿抢救 - 收到
- Stabilize in here? - Roger.
就在直升机里抢救 重复 就在这儿抢救
Stabilize in the bird. Repeat: Stabilize in here. Over.
收到了 韦基 我们替你们掩护
Understood, Wilkie. We got you covered. Over.
超级64号 去接替渥尔考特（超级61号）的位置
Super 64, come inbound and take Wolcott's position.
收到 64号进去了
Roger. 64 is inbound.
超级64号 你没事吧
Super 64, you all right?
这里是超级64号 我没事
This is Super 64. We're good.
确定吗 你的机身看来受损了
You sure? You look like you got clipped pretty good.
仪表板一切正常
Instrument panels are okay.
我们没事 就是机身有点晃动 不过没事
No, we're good. Got a slight vibration in the pedals, but we're good.
好吧 马上回机场降落 检查一下以策安全
All right, put her down on the airfield, 64. Have it checked out just to be safe.
收到
Roger.
机身晃动得很厉害 再检查一下系统
I'm getting a lot of movement in these pedals. Check the systems again.
尾桨失效了
We lost the tail rotor! It's gone!
64号正在坠落
64 is going down!
64 is going in hard.
64号正在坠落
64 going down.
我们正在坠落
We're going down.
快派史崔克的车队回去
Get Struecker's column back out there.
叫他们赶到杜兰特的坠机地点
They need to get to Durant's crash site fast.
- 又有一架直升机坠毁了 - 快去救他们
- Got another bird down. - I want them out of there.
把他们都救出来
All of them.
64完了
Super 64 is out.
什么
What?
他们是说另外一架黑鹰
They talking about another Hawk?
斯蒂尔上尉 再不前进就会受困
Captain Steele, we got to move or we're gonna get pinned down!
我们正在尽快前进
We're moving just as fast as we can.
你别管我的队伍
You let me do my job and you do yours. Over.
- 操 操 - 路兹 趴下
- Fuck! Fuck! - Ruiz, stay down.
- 我就知道… - 军医
- I fucking knew... - Medic.
去他的 斯蒂尔上尉 我来干掉那窗户的火力点
Fuck this! Captain Steele, I'll take out the threat in the window.
我们在灰色大楼集合 就冲进去 上尉
We'll rally point the gray building. Coming through, Captain.
什么
Sarg'nt!
好 行动
All right, let's move!
- 行动 快 - 行动 行动
- Let's move! Now! - Move! Move!
掩护我
Cover me!
- 走吧 行动 - 快离开
- Let's go, let's move! - Moving out.
友军
Friendly!
友军进来了
Friendlies coming through!
走吧 快走
Let's go, let's go! Move up!
快 快
Come on, come on!
快
Come on!
快走 走 快走
Move up! Go! Move up!
你在干什么鬼东西
What the fuck are you doing out there?
我在干我该干的 现在我们要赶到坠机地点
I'm doing my job! Now we got to get to that crash site!
我们一定要赶到那条街 要马上行动起来
We got to get out on that street, and we got to move!
而你也要跟上来
And you have got to keep up, sir!
别对我下令 军士长
Don't you ever give me orders, Sergeant.
我们没办法继续战斗 你知道吗
We are combat ineffective, you understand me?
有太多的伤员了
We got too many dang wounded to move!
那把你的一些人分给我 我带他们绕到坠机地点去
Then give me some of your shooters and I'll circle us to the bird.
格里姆斯 你是第四小队的吧
Grimes! You're with Chalk Four?
是的 长官
Yes, sir!
好 那就跟着"三角洲" 到埃利斯曼中士那里归队
All right, hook up with Delta! Rejoin with Sergeant Eversmann.
其他的人留守这里
The rest of you men, secure this position!
照顾好伤员 我们在这里等车队来
Treat the wounded, we'll wait for the convoy!
然后再去坠机地点会合
Then we'll rally at the crash site. Roger!
大家听到了 出发
Come on, guys, let's go!
C-2 我这里有两名"三角洲"的狙击手 舒加特和戈登…
C-2, I have two Delta snipers, Shughart and Gordon...
自愿前往保护第二坠机地点
volunteering to secure crash site two. Over.
不允许 超级62号 不能冒险再损失另一架直升机了
No, Super 62, negative that request. Can't risk another bird.
我们看不清那里的情况 不确定是否有人生还
We don't see anything moving down there now, we don't even know if anyone's alive.
地面部队正赶过去
A ground team is being organized to go in now.
地面部队多久能赶到
ETA on ground team? Over.
不清楚 但不用很长时间
Unknown, not long.
你们尽力从空中协助
Do what you can from the air.
来 大家过来集合
All right, gather around!
杜兰特的64号坠毁了 我们现在要去救他
Durant's 64 is down. We're going back in to get him!
你疯了 那里还有人生还吗
That's crazy. Is there anyone alive on that?
这没关系 总之绝决不抛弃同袍
Doesn't matter, no one gets left behind. You know that.
- 我们在浪费时间 - 好了
- We're wasting time here. - All right.
好啦 五分钟内重新武装起来 多带弹药
Refit and max out ammo and grenades, you got five!
西斯摩尔 你打算去什么鬼地方
Sizemore, where the hell do you think you're going?
- 跟你们一起去 - 你还伤着 不能去
- With you guys. - Not with that cast on you're not.
好啦 好啦 去拿头盔吧
All right, all right, all right. Go get your k-pot.
你说句话呀
Talk to me.
我不能再回去
I can't go back out there.
托马斯 大家都跟你一样害怕
Thomas, everyone feels the same way you do. All right?
所以你现在的表现才显得重要
It's what you do right now that makes a difference.
你自己决定吧
It's your call.
最好把悍马车上的血迹冲掉
It'll probably help to wash the blood out of the humvees.
史崔克中士
Sergeant Struecker!
史崔克中士 我能去吗
Sergeant Struecker! Can I go, Sarge?
- 你带够弹药了吗 - 带够了 中士
- You got some ammo? - Roger that, Sarge!
上车吧
Hop in!
等等
Wait!
来吧 托马斯 上车
Let's go, Thomas. Get in!
尼尔森 汤布里 请回答 我是杰利顿
Nelson, Twombly, come in. This is Galentine.
我们需要知道车队的位置
We need to position the convoy. Over.
尼尔森 汤布里 请回答 我是杰利顿
Nelson, Twombly, come in. This is Galentine. Over.
什么
What?
- 你刚才说什么了吗 - 什么
- You said something. What? - What?
好吧
Fine.
呼叫不上 中士 我呼叫不上他们
I can't raise him, Sergeant, I can't raise him.
中士 我们离开这鬼地方
Sergeant, let's get the fuck out of here and evac.
- 离开这儿 - 好吧
- Let's move out. - All right!
回到据点那儿
Back to the stronghold!
走
Come on.
走哪儿
Which way?
- 我想是那儿吧 - 小声点儿
- That way, I think! - Not so fucking loud.
乖驴子
Nice donkey.
是游骑兵
Rangers?
你谁呀
Who?
我是尤瑞克 你这混蛋
It's Yurek! You fucking assholes!
操
Fuck!
该死的 我们差点儿就干掉你了
Dude, we almost fucking killed you!
- 你快过来 - 操 你们过来这边
- Come to us! - Fuck you, come to me.
对不起 中士
Sorry, Sarge!
该死的 你刚才上哪儿了
Dude, where the fuck have you been?
这不要紧 你带夜视镜了吗
Never mind, you brought NOD, right?
我没带 你知道原因吗
No, I didn't bring it, and you want to know why?
因为你说过 我们半小时就回来了 用不着那玩意儿
Because you said: "You're not gonna need that, dude, we'll be back in a half-hour."
我不是这样跟你说的
No, I wasn't saying it to you.
尼尔森 掩护这条路
Nelson, cover this way.
我们需要夜视镜
Man, we're gonna need night vision.
你有什么毛病
What's the matter with you?
他聋了 是我的错
Oh, he's deaf. It's my fault.
- 我们一定得离开这儿 - 那边
- We need to get out of here! - That way.
我们不能离坠机地点太远 哪条路
We can't be far from the crash. Which way?
我以为你知道
I thought you might know.
出发吧
Let's move out.
地面部队占据着马雷汉大街上的几栋建筑物
Ground forces have occupied several buildings along Marehan Road...
但是都分散开来
but they're all spread out.
埃利斯曼中士的第四小队在渥尔考特的坠机地点建立了防线
Eversmann's Chalk Four has set up a perimeter around Wolcott's crash site here.
迪托马索在附近的大楼
DiTomasso is in the adjacent structure.
斯蒂尔上尉率领着大约40名游骑兵 在这儿 在两个街口外
Captain Steele and about 40 men, Rangers, are here, a couple blocks away.
他们的情况很惨
They're banged up pretty bad.
他设立了伤亡聚集点 我想他们没办法继续前进了
He set up a casualty collection point, I don't think they're gonna be able to move.
山德森军士和一小队"三角洲"…
Sergeant Sanderson and a small Delta team...
由斯蒂尔上尉那儿出发 正赶往坠机地点
are moving from Steele's position to the crash site as we speak.
吸引他们的火力
Draw off fire!
等那些该死的家伙装弹时 就掩护我
When this asshole stops to reload, cover me!
- 上 - 是
- Go! - Sir.
再来一遍
Again!
装弹
Loading!
继续 继续
Keep going! Keep going!
卡弹了
I'm jammed!
让我来
I got it!
该死的
No, shit!
RPG
RPG!
你还好吧 没事吧
You all right? You okay?
啊 我脑袋里好像在敲着钟
Yeah. I can hear bells ringing.
快 来吧
Come on! Come on!
走
Go!
距坠机地点六、七个街区外有一群人正在接近
There's a crowd advancing six, seven blocks from the crash.
舒加特和戈登再次请求…
Shughart and Gordon again request permission...
前往保护坠机地点 等车队到来
to secure until convoy arrives. Over.
将军 人群增加到好几百人
General, crowds are in the hundreds now.
他们看得会比我们清楚
From where they are, they can see things clearer than any of us.
他们很清楚自己的要求有多危险
They know what they're asking.
让我跟他们说
Let me talk to them.
这里是加里森
This is Garrison.
我要确定你们真的很清楚你们要求去干的事
I want to make sure that y'all understand what you're asking for...
请大声清楚地说出来
so say it out loud and clear.
我们要求到坠机地点建立防线并等待地面支援
We're asking to go in and set up a perimeter until ground support arrives.
你得清楚我无法告诉你要等多久 支援部队恐怕得花上好一阵子
And you realize that I cannot tell you when that might be, it could take a while.
- 明白 - 那你们还是要去
- Roger that. - You still want to go in there?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
- 哈勒尔上校 - 是 将军
- Colonel Harrell? - Yes, General?
你来决定吧
It's your call.
明白
Roger that.
高夫纳（超级62号的机长） 把他们送过去
Goffena, put them in.
草泥马 草泥马
Motherfucker. Motherfucker.
RPG
RPG!
建立防线
Set up your perimeter!
这枚该死的火箭弹就插在他身上
There's a fucking rocket in him, sir!
奥西克 冷静点 该死的 它随时会爆炸 快走开
Othic, calm down, goddamn it! There's live ordnance, now get out!
这婊子养的
Son of a bitch.
来 把他抬起来 小心点 小心
All right, lift him up! Lift him up! Easy, easy!
好了 把他移进车里 很好 小心 小心
All right, get him in there! Good, good! Easy, easy!
快上车 开车
Get in that truck and drive.
- 我受伤了 上校 - 我们都受了伤
- But I'm shot, Colonel. - Everybody's shot.
我们得把犯人押回去
We need the prisoners! Let's go!
侦察机说你先开到哈瓦迪街再直走
Surveillance says to take Hawlwadig, then go straight.
麦肯奈特 你得掉头 回到哈瓦迪街
McKnight, we need you to turn around and head back to Hawlwadig.
你在糊弄我吗 我们才从那儿过来
You're shitting me! We just came through there!
肯定有更好的路线
There's gotta be a better route!
这是联合指挥中心的情报 你得掉头回去
That's the info I'm getting from JOC, you need to turn around and head back.
明白 明白
Roger that. Roger that.
我可不信这鬼话 掉头吧 马多克斯
I cannot believe this shit! Turn us around, Maddox.
长官 他们（指C-2）是想把我们都害死在这儿吧
They're trying to get us all fucking killed, aren't they, sir?
快离开这儿 开车
Just get it over with! Drive!
该死
God damn!
快带我们离开这儿 该死的 开车
Get us out of here, God damn it, drive!
继续踩油门
Keep your foot on the gas!
操
Fuck!
该死
Shit.
C-2 舒加特和戈登落地了
C-2, Shughart and Gordon are on the deck. Over.
收到
Roger.
是友军
Friendlies!
天啊 见到你们真好
God, it's good to see you!
我也是 你伤有多重
It's good to see you. How bad?
我的腿断了 而且我的背很痛
My leg's broken and my back feels kind of weird.
我们把你救出去 伙计
We've got to get you out of here, buddy.
我把他拉出来了 掩护我
I'm pulling him out! Cover!
等等…
Wait, I...
我把你放下来
I'm putting you down.
C-2 我们在64号坠机地点建立防线
C-2, we're at the 64 crash site, securing perimeter.
收到
Roger that.
- 你还行吗 - 还好
- You all right? - Yeah, I'm good.
枪上膛了
You're locked and loaded.
后面有敌人就帮我们解决掉
Any skinnies come around these corners, you watch our backs.
救援班就是指在第一坠机地点索降的那群扑街
- 救援班呢 - 我们就是了
- Where's the rescue squad? - We're it.
C-2 请报告车队的情况
C-2, you keep talking about the convoy.
我要知道他们在哪儿
I'd like to know where in hell it is. Over.
车队遇到阻力越来越大了
The perimeter has to be tighter for the convoy.
你们离坠机地点还太远
You're too far from the crash.
散开行动 自己突围
Stay spread out like that and you're all liable to be overrun.
好吧 停车 马多克斯 停车
All right, stop, stop, Maddox. Stop.
那婊子养的
Son of a bitch.
R64号 我们又回到原点了
Romeo 64, we're right back where we started.
弹药快用完了 而且大家都受了伤
I'm running low on ammo, I got many wounded including me...
车子也几乎跑不起了
vehicles that are barely running.
好吧 丹尼 你就实说吧
Okay, Danny, I need a no-b.s. assessment here.
你能到达坠机地点吗
Can you get to the crash site?
上校 我什么也看不到
Colonel, I can't see shit.
不能
Negative.
伤员太多 我们去了也没用
With the amount of wounded we have, we'd do more harm than good.
我们要回基地补充弹药然后再回来
We need to come back to base, rearm and regroup and then we can go back out.
明白
Roger.
C-2 叫他们回来 带他们离开那儿
C-2, bring them back. Get them out of there.
明白 返回基地吧
Roger. Return to base.
我们要回去了
We're going home!
走吧 左转
Let's go. Left.
下午4:54
收到了 明白 车队要返回基地
Roger that. Understand. Convoy returning to base.
- 怎么回事 - 车队被叫回去了
- What's up? - They're sending them back.
车队要回基地
The convoy's headed back to base camp.
这可太妙了
Oh, now that makes sense, don't it?
我们要赶紧把伤员送回去 然后才来这儿
We need to exfil the wounded now and get the hell out of here before it's too late!
麦肯奈特中校先回基地是有理由的
If Colonel McKnight went back to base, then he had a good reason.
我们的任务不变
It changes nothing.
大伙儿听好
All right, listen up.
我们要顶住防线 要守住这个据点
We're going to hold the perimeter and we're going to hold the strongpoint.
节约弹药 有必要才开枪
Conserve your ammo. Only shoot at what you can hit.
车队一定会回来的
The convoy is going to come.
我们一定能回家
We're going to get home.
装弹
Loading!
兰迪 我要手枪弹匣
Randy, I need a pistol mag!
装弹
Loading!
兰迪 最后一个弹匣
Randy, last mag!
戈登
Gordy!
操
Fuck!
戈登死了 我出去拼了
Gordy is gone, man. I'll be outside.
祝你好运
Good luck.
我们需要第十山地师的帮助 他们在这里有什么就要什么
We need the 10th Mountain in there. Everything they got.
还有巴基斯坦和马来西亚 我需要他们的坦克和装甲人员输送车
Pakistanis, Malays, I want their tanks and APCs.
他们不知道我们的行动
They don't know we've gone in.
瞧 我们捅了马蜂窝 这里 我们是在跟整个城市作战
Look, we have stirred up the hornet's nest here. We're fighting the entire city.
我需要所有的车辆 不管是装甲车还是什么 快去要回来 有什么要什么
I want every vehicle possible that's got 4 wheels and armor. Get it. Get everything.
一旦把部队集结起来 就去把我们的人救出敌对地区
Now, once they've assembled, we're gonna move our men out of the hostile area...
送到位于安全区内的巴基斯坦体育场
and back to the Pakistani Stadium, the safe zone.
- 马上执行 - 遵命 长官
- Now, let's go. - Roger that, boss.
穆罕默德・艾迪德
要活捉…
这名战俘
跪下 跪下
On your knees! Get down! Get down!
撑着点 你只是大腿中弹
Stay with me. You just got a bullet in the leg.
你看到烧轮胎的黑烟吗
See where those tires are burning? All that black smoke?
我看到了 但我到不了那儿
Roger. I can see it, but I can't get there. Over.
坠机地点离那儿只有一百米
Go 100 meters past it. That's the crash.
不行 你不明白
Negative. You don't understand.
前面路障连着路障 你得另找一条路
It's roadblock after roadblock. You have to find us another route. Over.
另一条路要绕过整座城市
There ain't one. The only other route is all the way around the city.
收到
Roger that.
K64号 这里是K11号
Kilo 64, this is Kilo 11.
请求准许我步行到达坠机地点
Request permission to move to crash site number two on foot. Over.
好的 K11号
Green light, Kilo 11.
停车 让我下去
Stop the vehicle. Let me out.
下午5:50
- 什么 - 你听到什么了
- What? - Don't you hear that?
- 是车队吗 - 不 不是车队
- Is it the convoy? - No. No, it's not the convoy.
等完事以后 回去我要好好请你们喝一杯
After I'm finished with this, I'll whip you boys up some margaritas.
玛格丽特调酒 不加盐
The usual. Blended, no salt.
这里是K12号 我们要移动阵地了
This is Kilo 12. We've got to change our position. Over.
埃利斯曼 请回答
Eversmann, come in.
埃利斯曼
Eversmann.
- 收到 你是谁 - 山德森
- Roger, who is this? - Sanderson.
千万别向东边开枪 我们要过来了
Do not... l say again, do not fire to the east. We are coming to you.
明白
Understood.
迪托马索他们在东南角
DiTomasso and his men are on the southeast corner.
你们要占领东北角的建筑
We need you on the northeast building.
收到 没问题
Roger. We'll take it.
小心敌人 他们都在屋顶
Watch out for skinnies. They're all over the rooftops.
他们的祷告快要结束了
They're in prayer but not for much longer.
别向东边开火
Hold your fire to the east.
埃利斯曼 这里是尤瑞克
Eversmann? It's Yurek.
尼尔森和汤布里跟我在一起
I got Nelson and Twombly with me.
我们看到直升机了 你在哪里
We got the chopper in sight. Where are you?
我们在西南角
We're on the southwest corner.
你们到底在哪 你没事吧
Where the hell have you been? Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
别开枪 我们过来了
Hold your fire. We're coming in.
现在我们走
We got to go.
肖恩 听好 尤瑞克中士先跑
Shawn! Shawn, listen! Sergeant Yurek's going to run first.
等他过了马路…
When he gets across the street...
他就会转过头来掩护你跑过去
he's gonna turn around and he's gonna cover you as you run.
听清楚了 等你到了那儿…
Listen closely. When you get there...
再掉头过来掩护我
you're gonna turn around and you're gonna cover me, okay?
你不能直接就跑去埃利斯曼那里
You're not gonna just run to Eversmann's position.
你要停下来 掩护我
You're gonna stop, you're gonna turn around and you are gonna cover me.
你一定要搞清楚这点
It's important you understand that.
好了吗
Okay, you ready?
准备好了
Yeah, I guess.
- 可别忘了 - 什么
- Don't forget. - What?
别忘了
Don't forget.
我看到他们了 他们从西边的大门进来了
I got them in my sight, Sarg'nt. They're coming up on the west gate.
我看到了
I see them.
出去吧
Let's move out.
你们能掩护我们吗 中士
Can you cover us, Sergeant?
没问题
We got you.
尼尔森
Nelson!
可恶
Fuck!
汤布里
Twombly!
史密斯 不
Smith! No!
你没事吧
You all right?
快弄掉 快
Get it off of me!
快弄掉
Get it off!
快走 快走
Come on, man. Come on.
医生 快来救史密斯
Doc! Need some help with Smith here!
我的腿 我的腿
My leg! My leg!
我帮你 杰米
Come on, Jamie, I got you!
抬起来 一二三
Up, one, two, three.
- 你会没事的 - 用力压住他的伤口
- You're all right. - I need pressure on this wound.
我的右腿
My right thigh!
用力压
Pressure, yeah.
- 我的蛋蛋还在吧 - 蛋蛋还在
- Are my balls okay? - You still have your balls.
我需要人帮忙
I need more men in here.
汤布里 尼尔森
Twombly! Nelson!
- 把他按下去 - 天哪 这…
- Put him down. - Oh, man, that really...
把椅子给我
I need that chair.
- 很痛啊 - 直接压住
- It really hurts! - Direct pressure on that.
没事的 没事
It's okay, it's okay.
- 让我看看 - 没事
- Let me see it! - All right.
来 我先看看怎么样
All right, let me get a look at that.
该死的
Oh, shit!
操
Oh, fuck!
- 怎么回事 - 没事
- What the fuck was that? - It's all right.
按住 要马上救治才行
Hold that down. I need a medivac now.
操 杰利顿
Fuck. Galentine!
没事的
It's all right.
杰利顿 快帮我接斯蒂尔上尉
Galentine! Get me Captain Steele!
- 路兹 你还好吧 - J64号 请回答
- Sarg'nt Ruiz, how you doing? - Juliet 64, come in. Over.
他们不会来接我们了 他们不会来了
They're not going to come and get us. They're not going to come for us.
给我闭嘴 振作点 打起精神来
I need you to suck it up, Sarg'nt. I need you to focus for me.
- 好啦 你做得到吗 - J64号 请回答
- All right? Can you do that? - Juliet 64, come in. Over.
你还能开枪吗
Now, can you hold your weapon?
可以 长官
Yes, sir.
如果谁敢闯进来…
Anybody comes through that door...
先往他胸部打两枪 再往脑袋上打一枪
you give him two in the chest and one in the head.
- 明白了吗 - 我还能战斗 长官
- You understand? - I'm still in the fight, sir.
斯蒂尔上尉 我们这里有人需要救治
Captain Steele, I need a medivac in here now!
- 史密斯下士中弹了 - 等一下 25号
- Corporal Smith has been hit! - Hold on, 25.
我还可以打仗
Still in the fight.
斯蒂尔上尉 他伤得很重
Captain Steele, he's hurt pretty bad.
25号 我们这里也有很多伤员 你只能暂时在原地处理
25, we got wounded, too. You're just gonna have to maintain your situation, over.
如果半小时里不把他送进医院 就会没命了
If he doesn't get to a hospital in a half-hour, he's in trouble!
C-2 这里是64号
C-2, this is 64.
我们请求派遣医疗救援
I'm requesting an immediate medivac...
在第四小队那里有危重伤员
for a critically wounded at Chalk Four's location. Over.
指挥部 第四小队请求医疗救援
Command, Chalk Four is requesting medivac.
不能冒险 战况还很激烈
Can't risk it. It's still too hot.
上尉 我们不能派出医疗救援 请支持下去
Captain, we cannot send in medivac at this time. Sit tight. Over.
25号 这里是64号 无法派遣医疗救援 他们办不到
25, this is 64. It's a negative on the medivac. It's not possible.
联合指挥部不打算再派另一架直升机去冒险 你们要自己坚持下去
JOC cannot risk another bird. You're just gonna have to hold on.
好吧 我们自己来
All right. I got him.
直接压在伤口上
I want direct pressure on the wound.
你不会有事的 会好起来的
It's going to be all right. It's going to be okay.
这是我们的直升机
这里是K11号 我到了杜兰特的坠机地点
This is Kilo 11. I'm at the Durant crash site.
收到
Roger that.
第二坠机地点清除
Crash site two secured.
克里布斯中校找你 长官
Lieutenant Colonel Cribbs for you, sir.
克里布斯
Cribbs?
巴基斯坦体育场 第十山地师和联合国维和部队基地
- 长官 他们还在讨论路线 - 还要多久
- Sir, they're still debating the route. - How long?
还要好几个小时
At least a couple of hours.
我们等不了那么长的时间 乔
We haven't got that long, Joe.
巴基斯坦将军说我们事先没有通知他们这次行动
Pakistani General says, since we didn't deign to inform him of the raid...
而且把第十山地师和一百辆车发动起来要花点时间
it's gonna take some time to mobilize the 10th Mountain and 100 vehicles.
你告诉那个将军
You tell the general this:
我知道 但我也要提醒他
I understand, but it is my duty to remind him...
我的手下被武装民兵团团包围
that my men are surrounded by thousands of armed Somali militia.
我们必须立刻把他们救出敌对区域 送进安全区
It is imperative that we move them out of the hostile area and into the safe zone.
我现在就需要他的帮助
I need his help now.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
杜兰特
Durant.
迈克尔・杜兰特
Michael Durant.
是的
Yes.
你就是那些杀害我同胞的游骑兵
You are the Ranger who kills my people?
我不是游骑兵 我是飞行员
I'm not a Ranger. I'm a pilot.
那就对了
That's right.
美国人不抽烟了
None of you Americans smoke anymore.
你们都过着无趣的生活
You all live long, dull, uninteresting lives.
你为什么要抓我
What do you want with me?
你们手上有我们的人质
You have taken hostages.
我们手上有你
We have you.
美国政府才不会跟你谈判
My government will never negotiate for me.
那么我就跟你谈判吧
Then perhaps you and I can negotiate, huh?
我们都是军人
Soldier to soldier.
我作不了决定的
I'm not in charge.
当然不能 你有能力杀人 却没有能力谈判
Of course not. You have the power to kill, but not negotiate.
在索马里 杀人就是谈判
In Somalia, killing is negotiation.
你们真的以为你们抓到了艾迪德将军
Do you really think if you get General Aidid...
我们就会放下武器
we will simply put down our weapons...
接受美式民主
and adopt American democracy?
或是停止杀戮吗
That the killing will stop?
我只知道没有胜利就没有和平
We know this: Without victory, there can be no peace.
杀戮永远不会停止
There will always be killing, you see?
这就是我们的方式
This is how things are in our world.
迈克・杜兰特 我们不会抛弃你
Mike Durant, we won't leave you behind.
换你来 用双手按住
You got to take over from me. Both hands.
伤口在股动脉 但是我看不到
It's the femoral artery, but I can't see it.
它一定缩进骨盆内了
Which means that it's retracted up into the pelvis.
我必须把伤口找出来 用止血钳把它夹住才能止血
Which means that I have to find it and clamp it. The only way to stop the bleeding.
但麻醉剂用完了
I got no more IV's.
所以我要你帮忙 好吗
So, I'm going to need you to assist. Okay?
好的
Yeah, yeah.
听好 杰米 我要做一件事 但会很痛的
Now listen, Jamie. I got to do something, it's going to hurt.
好吗
Okay?
你会很痛的 不过只有这样我才能救你
I got to cause you more pain, but I have to do it to help you.
你听懂了吗
All right, you understand?
- 吗啡呢 - 不能用
- Morphine. - I can't.
那会长时间降低你的心跳的
It'll lower your heart rate too far. I'm sorry.
汤布里 抓紧他的手
Twombly, why don't you take his hands there?
我要把伤口撑开 紧紧压住他的大腿
I need you to hold the wound open, keep pressure on the top of the leg.
尤瑞克 你也抓住一只脚 顺便帮我拿着手电筒
Yurek, you're gonna take the feet and a flashlight.
听我数数
On my count.
准备好了 杰米
All right, Jamie. All right.
一 二…
One. Two.
三
Three.
等等 好 找到了
Wait, wait. Okay. I feel it.
我找到了
I feel the pulse.
I got it. I got it.
我找到了 我找到了
I got it, yeah. I got it.
- 我找到了 - 你找到什么
- I got it. - You got it?
钳住伤口了
Clamp?
我钳住了
I got it clamped.
- 坚持住 - 钳住它
- Hold it. - Got it.
这里 快抓住
Here, grab it.
- 撕开它 - 我找到了
- It's tearing. - I got it.
- 医生 它又缩回去了 - 抓住它
- Doc, it's going back in! - Hold it!
撕开了
It's tearing!
- 好 撑开伤口 - 撑开了
- Okay. Get out. Hold the wound. - Okay, I'm holding.
把手拿开
Move your hand.
怎么了
What?
治好了吗
Fix it?
是的 治好了
Yeah, yeah. We got it.
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
磨咖啡豆的关键是不能磨得太细 也不能太粗
It's all in the grind, Sarg'nt. Can't be too fine, can't be too coarse.
格里姆斯 你弄好了
Grimesy, you are squared away.
军士 来一杯热腾腾的咖啡吧
Sarg'nt, how would you like a nice hot cup of Joe?
黄金海岸口味的
Gold Coast blend.
坐下来 我看看你的伤口
Sit down. I want to take a look at that foot.
- 没什么大不了的 - 坐下吧
- No, it's not a problem. - Come on, come on.
- 他们从哪儿把你找来的 - 办公桌后面
- Where the hell did they find you? - Behind a desk.
是真的 我没开玩笑
No, really. What, you think I'm kidding?
- 有人受伤吗 - 没有
- Is anybody hit? - We're good!
你们没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah!
大家都没事吧
Is everybody all right?
没事
Yeah!
敌袭
Incoming!
继续开火 快点
迪托马索中弹 把他救出去
DiTomasso's hit! Pull him out!
游骑兵 这里是K11号
Ranger here. This is Kilo 11.
我们是第四小队 在坠机地点的东南角 你是谁
This is Chalk Four. We're at the southeast corner of the crash site. Who's this? Over.
这位绰号Hoot的三角洲队员全名是Norm Hooten
这里是胡特 我带了三名友军一起进来了
This is Hoot. I'm coming in with three friendlies.
我需要掩护火力
I need some cover and fire. Over.
收到 K11号 停止射击 三角洲要进来了
Roger that, Kilo 11 . Hold your fire! Deltas coming in.
停止射击 停止射击
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
让地面部队用红外求生灯标出目标位置
Ground personnel will have to mark target positions with infrared strobes.
然后让AH-6"小鸟"整晚地扫射敌人
Get little birds on strafing runs and keep them going all night long.
如果我们控制不住那里的状况
If we don't hold back this city...
到明早就可能要准备上百口棺材了
we'll have a 100 caskets to fill by morning.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
哈勒尔上校 通知第一坠机地点的地面部队
Colonel Harrell, ground personnel at crash site one...
用红外求生灯把目标标出来 方便我们空袭
will have to mark the target with infrared strobes in preparation for air strike.
巴基斯坦体育场
麦肯奈特
McKnight.
第十山地师和联合国维和部队就够人了
Between the 10th Mountain and U.N., we got enough personnel, okay?
丹尼 你们不必再回去
Danny, you guys do not have to go back out again.
晚上11:23
我不能死在这儿
I can't die here, man.
你不会死的 懂吗 你不会死
You're not going to die, all right? You're not going to die.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不必道歉
You don't have anything to be sorry for.
你救了汤布里 你做得很好
You saved Twombly. You did perfect.
汤布里 你没事吧
You okay, Twombs?
杰米 我没事
Yeah, I'm okay, Jamie.
你是个好军人
You did what you were trained to do.
你应该感到骄傲
You should be proud of that.
和自豪
Be proud of that.
- 埃文 - 在
- Ev? - Yeah.
帮我一个忙
Do me a favor.
嗯
Yeah.
跟我父母说 我今天很英勇
You tell my parents that I fought well today.
说我…
That l...
我尽力了
And that I fought hard.
你自己亲口对他们说吧
You're going to tell them yourself, okay?
知道吗
Do you hear me?
好吗
All right?
- 悍马车队来了吗 - 来了 杰米
- Are the humvees here? - They're coming, Jamie.
他们来了
They're coming.
你只要再撑一下
You just got to hang in there a little bit.
- 再多撑一下子 - 小意思
- You hold on for just a little bit. - I can.
我行的
I can.
没问题
It's nothing.
- 没问题 - 没问题
- It's nothing. - It's nothing.
没问题
Nothing.
可恶
Oh, shit.
压住伤口
Hold the wound.
医生
Doc.
行了
It's okay.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我们需要弹药
We need the ammo.
你已经尽了力
You did all you could here.
他们应该派医疗队来的
They should've sent a medivac.
它一定会被击落的 我们没法再防守一个坠机地点
Right now we'd be out there defending another crashed chopper.
会有更多的人受伤
More men would get torn up.
也许吧
Maybe.
别想那么多
See, you're thinking. Don't.
中士 你不能决定让谁来受伤
Because, Sergeant, you can't control who gets hit or who doesn't.
或是谁从直升机上摔落
Who falls out of a chopper or why.
这就是战争 你也无能为力
It ain't up to you. It's just war.
是的 但史密斯还是死了
Yeah, well, Smith's still dead.
都是因为布莱克博德摔下来 然后才发生那么多事
If Blackburn wouldn't have fallen, none of this would have happened.
你想这么多也没用
Should have or could have, it don't matter.
以后你有的是时间去想
You'll get plenty of time to think about all that later. Believe me.
中士 你把弟兄们带到这儿
Sergeant, you got your men this far.
你已经尽了全力
You did it right today.
现在你要想该怎么把他们带出去了
You need to start thinking about getting these men out of here.
可以走了吗
Well, shall we?
我要四个人守住这角落
I need four guys in this corner now!
RPG
RPG!
这里是巴伯52号 准备好扫射了
This is Barber 52 in position for gun run.
老天爷 你看看
Jesus Christ. Look at that.
这里是25号 我看到了 你就在我上方
This is 25! I can see you. You're right above me.
埃利斯曼 我分不清敌友了 这里太混乱了
Eversmann, I can't tell who's who down there. Too much activity.
我会用红外求生灯把目标标示出来
I'll mark the target with a strobe! Over.
收到
Roger that.
看到了吗
You see it?
不 我什么都看不到
Nah, I can't see shit.
- 我要丢到屋顶 - 得有人帮你才行
- I'm putting it on the roof. - You're going to need some help!
掩护我
Cover me.
好 大家听我数到三 就开枪掩护他
Okay, guys, we're going to lay down some cover fire for him on three!
准备好了
Ready?
一
One.
二
Two.
三 上
Three. Go!
我看到目标了 准备进行扫射
I got your position. I got the target. We're inbound and hot.
把头低下 我们再扫射一圈
Y'all keep your heads down. We're coming back around.
收到了 C-4
Copy that, C-4.
C-2 这里是64号 车队在哪 我们还呆在这鬼地方
C-2, this is 64. Where the hell is the convoy? We're getting fucked here. Over.
在半路上 你们继续坚守阵地
You're half a click from your location. Hang in there.
可恶
Shit!
C-2 弹药扫光了 请求返回基地补充
C-2, miniguns dry. Request permission to return to base. Rearm. Over.
收到 第二队接入 进入火力支援区
Roger that. Second team inbound. Your station.
四分钟后进入攻击位置
On your location, four minutes.
他们来了 把伤员运上去
All right, they're here. Get the wounded ready to move.
快 快
Move! Move!
趴好 掩护我们
Lay down some cover fire!
我早就听到你们了
I thought I heard a noise out here!
让你的人上车 我们离开这鬼地方
Get your men loaded up. We're getting the hell out of here.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
25号 这里是64号 营救纵队已经到我们这儿了
25, this is 64. The rescue column has arrived.
大约五分钟后到你们那儿
Will be at your location in about 5 minutes.
让你的人做好撤退准备
Prepare your men for exfil, Sarg'nt.
收到 长官 收到了
Yeah, roger that, sir! Roger that!
五分钟 车队五分钟后就到
Five minutes! The convoy is going to be here in five minutes!
我要弹匣 埃利斯曼 我的弹药用完了
I need a mag! Eversmann, I'm out!
最后一个了
Here! It's my last one!
凌晨2:05
车队来了
The convoy is here!
埃利斯曼中士 听说你们要搭便车
Sergeant Eversmann. I heard you guys needed a lift!
是的 长官
Yes, sir!
把伤员抬上来
Bring your wounded right over there and start loading them up!
来 我来扶你
Hey, I got you. I got you.
没关系 我想走走
It's okay. I want to walk.
我也一样 走吧
Yeah, I would, too. Let's go!
走 快走
Move! Move!
我们把驾驶员的尸体拉出来就回体育场
We get the pilots' bodies out, and then we go to the stadium.
车上没有地方了
We're running out of room around here.
尽量挤一挤
Just gonna have to cram into every possible space.
第十山地师用装甲车保护我们从交战区撤退
Okay, 10th Mountain provides security for armor, walks us out of the hot zone.
第十山地师 不
10th Mountain? No.
我们游骑兵就可以殿后
Sir, with respect, my Rangers can provide rear security.
我们走出交战区再坐车
We'll walk you out of the hot zone, then we'll jump on the last few vehicles.
好 出发吧
Okay, let's get out of here.
出发
Let's go.
来吧
- All right, you got him? - Yeah, come on.
开车呀
Come on!
我们现在就在吸引子弹 快走吧
These things are fucking bullet magnets. Come on, let's go!
我们接到命令才能走 士兵
We go when I'm ordered to, soldier.
小心点
Careful.
小心 小心
Easy. Go easy.
小心
Easy.
上校 怎么回事
Colonel, what is going on down there?
他们要绕着尸体来拆开驾驶舱
They're dismantling the entire cockpit around the body.
还要多久 实话实说
How long is it going to take? I need an honest, no-shit assessment.
说不准
They can't say!
丹尼
Danny...
绝对不能抛弃同袍
no one gets left behind.
你明白吗
You understand me, son?
明白 将军
Yes, General.
该怎么做就怎么做
You do what you have to do.
收到
Roger.
- 还要多久 - 45分钟
- How much longer? - Forty-five minutes.
- 我们等不了45分钟 - 什么
- We don't have 45 minutes. - What?
我们等不了45分钟 懂吗
We don't have 45 minutes. Do you understand?
明白吗
Do you understand?
好吧
Okay.
- 快 把他抬出来 - 好了
- All right, come on. Bring him through. - I got him.
- 把伤员都救出来 - 来了
- Get all of his gear. Get the wounded out. - Got you, sir!
10月4日 星期一 早上5:45
- 快 快 快 - 来了
- Go! Move! - Got you!
快走 快走
Move out! Move out! Let's go!
操
Fuck!
要炸了
Fire in the hole!
- 走吧 快走 - 走
- Let's go! Move! - Let's go! Let's go!
- 开舱门 让我们进去 - 挤不下了 坐车顶吧
- Open up the hatch! We got men back here! - No room here! Go on the roof!
怎么回事
What's going on?
- 车顶 - 我才不坐车顶
- The roof? - I'm not getting on no fucking roof!
没地方坐了
No, no, it's full.
跑吧 继续前进 用车子作掩护
We're running out. Keep moving. Use the vehicles as cover.
走吧 出发
Move it! Let's go!
等一下 等一下
All right, hold it up. Hold it up.
- 快走 - 快走
- Move! - Go! Move!
快
Go!
趴下 趴下
Get down! Get down!
快趴下
Get down, lady!
我没子弹了
I'm out of ammo!
山德森 我没子弹了
Sanderson, I'm out of ammo!
别拿枪
Don't you do it.
- 你在干嘛 - 别去拿枪
- What are you doing? - Don't you damn do it.
库尔特 走吧
Kurth, let's go!
小心 小心
Easy. Easy.
啊 该死的
Ah, shit.
子弹错过你的颈静脉了 别动
Bullet missed your jugular by about three millimeters. Don't move.
下次看准点 走吧
Aim later. Go!
走
Go!
动作快点
Hurry up, hurry up.
嘿 别让他自个儿爬 帮帮他
Hey, don't let that man crawl. Somebody help that man.
帮帮他
Help him.
格里姆斯 干得好
Grimes, you did good.
该死
Oh, shit!
浴场在哪儿 少校
Where are the baths, Major?
从这儿过去就是 上尉
They're through there, Captain.
路兹
Ruiz.
嘿 中士
Hey, Sarg'nt. Hey.
上尉
Captain.
洛伦佐 你还好吧
Lorenzo. How you doing?
子弹擦过去 军医说我过两天就好了
It went in and out, so the medic said I should be okay in a couple of days.
真是好消息
That's great news.
我们要回去吗
We're going after them?
当然了 不过我们得先重整队伍
You bet your ass we will. We got to regroup.
别把我留下来
Don't go out without me.
别丢下我就回去
Don't go back out there without me.
我还能打仗
I can still do my job.
好好休息吧
You get some rest now, okay?
格里姆斯
Grimes.
没咖啡 我给你倒点茶吧
Little short on coffee, but I got you some tea.
还好吗 士兵
How you doing, soldier?
没感觉了
Can't feel a thing.
你要回去
You're going back in?
在那里还有弟兄
There are still men out there.
该死
God damn.
我每次回家
When I go home...
他们都问我
and people ask me:
胡特 你为什么从军
"Hey, Hoot, why do you do it, man?"
难道你是打仗打上瘾了吗
"Why? You some kind of war junkie?"
我一句话也说不出来
I won't say a goddamn word.
为什么
Why?
他们不会懂
They won't understand.
他们不懂我们干嘛要打仗
They won't understand why we do it.
我们是为了袍泽而拼命
They won't understand it's about the men next to you.
就这么简单
And that's it.
很简单
That's all it is.
想都别想 我习惯单枪匹马
Hey, don't even think about it, all right? I'm better on my own.
星期一 又是一周的开始
Hey, we started a whole new week. It's Monday.
过几天 布莱克博德问我
I was talking to Blackburn the other day...
什么改变了 我们为什么要回家
and he asked me, "What changed? Why are we going home?"
我说什么都没变
And I said, "Nothing."
但这不是实话 我想 一切都变了
But that's not true, you know. I think everything's changed.
我也变了
I know I've changed.
曾经有一个朋友问我
A friend of mine asked me before I got here...
那是在我们被派来这儿之前
It was when we were all shipping out.
他问我
He asked me:
你为什么要去打别人的仗
"Why are you going to fight somebody else's war?"
你自以为是英雄吗
"What, do y'all think you're heroes?"
当时我不知道该说什么
I didn't know what to say at the time...
现在我的答案是 不
but if he asked me again, I'd say no.
我不想当英雄
I'd say there's no way in hell.
没有人想当英雄
Nobody asks to be a hero.
只是时势造英雄
It just sometimes turns out that way.
回家后 我会去找你的父母
I'm gonna talk to your ma and pa when I get home, okay?
一千多名索马里人死亡
十九名美军阵亡
我的爱 你会坚强地活下去
My love, you are strong and you will do well in life.
我爱你和我的孩子
I love you and my children deeply.
每一天都会茁壮成长
Today and tomorrow, let each day grow and grow.
保持笑容 千万别被困境打倒
Keep smiling and never give up, even when things get you down.
最后 我的爱
So, in closing, my love...
今晚替我哄我的孩子入睡
tonight, tuck my children in bed warmly.
跟他们说我爱他们 替我拥抱他们…
Tell them I love them. Then hug them for me...
替爸爸亲吻他们 给他们道晚安
and give them both a kiss good night for Daddy.
"三角洲"的加里・戈登军士和兰迪・舒加特军士
是越战之后第一次
获追赠荣誉勋章的士兵
迈克・杜兰特被囚禁十一天后获释
两星期后 克林顿总统命令从索马里撤军
威廉・加里森少将为这次突击行动负起全责
1996年8月2日穆罕默德・艾迪德遭刺杀
翌日 加里森少将退役